Josh Woodcock // Full-Stack Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w00 // www.j0w0.com // www.linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

Full-Stack Software Engineer with four years of development experience building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies, improving analytics, and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

Skills/Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Google Firebase, MongoDB, Express, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Cloud-based Deployment Services (AWS, Heroku, Netlify), Styled Components, Bootstrap, jQuery, PHP, Git, RESTful APIs (Google, Stripe, Twilio), Wordpress, WooCommerce, Photoshop, Illustrator.

Demos: React demos include Celebrity Name Game and Event Manager. Tic-Tac-Toe (Robots vs. Babies), Simon, and Rock, Paper, Scissors are developed with vanilla Javascript. Code and more information is available on my GitHub.

Experience

Front-End Software Engineer

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-Present | Austin, Texas (Remote)

- Develops front end of brand and artist livestream web apps that provide fans with the ultimate digital music experience. Features include event registration and voting, real-time chat, tips / donations via Stripe, and livestream video feed.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase.

Front-End / UX Developer

Remedy | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that saw an increase in appointments by over 1000% and helped win two stages of VC funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the booking / scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes Wordpress, PHP, MySQL, Twilio, WooCommerce.

MIS Web Developer

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Designed and developed corporate website, allowing for easier management and sharing of content utilizing Wordpress.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.

Digital Media Marketing Coordinator

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

• Oversaw the production of all email campaigns and web graphics, as well as maintained corporate website content, event landing pages, and company Intranet.

Education

Texas State University

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Communication Design | San Marcos, Texas | May 2014

General Assembly

Software Engineering Immersive | Austin, Texas | October 2020